<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Ishmam Hossain</title><link>https://ishmam-hossain.github.io/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Ishmam Hossain</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©ishmam.dev@gmail.com</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ishmam-hossain.github.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pytest &amp; it's plugin architecture</title><link>https://ishmam-hossain.github.io/posts/pytest-plugin-architecture/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ishmam-hossain.github.io/posts/pytest-plugin-architecture/</guid><description>pytest is a popular Python testing framework that provides a flexible and extensible way to write tests for your code. One of the key strengths of pytest is its plugin architecture, which allows you to customize and extend the behavior of the framework to meet your specific needs.
One such plugin is pytest-django, which provides support for testing Django applications with pytest. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a closer look at the plugin architecture of pytest and pytest-django and explore how plugins can be used to customize and enhance the testing process.</description></item><item><title>Pivoting a Multi-Index Pandas DataFrame</title><link>https://ishmam-hossain.github.io/posts/pivoting-a-multi-index-pandas-dataframe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ishmam-hossain.github.io/posts/pivoting-a-multi-index-pandas-dataframe/</guid><description>Pandas is a popular Python library for data analysis and manipulation. It provides a powerful data structure called the DataFrame, which is similar to a table in a relational database. DataFrames can have multiple levels of index, which can make them challenging to work with. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to pivot a multi-index Pandas DataFrame to create a new DataFrame with columns and rows.
Suppose we have a Pandas DataFrame that looks like this:</description></item></channel></rss>